<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<projects>
  <project>
    <customername>Karthikeya</customername>
    <address>426 Westcott street</address>
    <topic>Ip</topic>
    <date>Monday, January 1, 0001</date>
    <textblock>Do it Well</textblock>
  </project>
  <project>
    <customername>rpa</customername>
    <address>416 comstock</address>
    <topic>name</topic>
    <date>Monday, January 1, 0001</date>
    <textblock>"Tendulkar" redirects here. For other people with the same surname, see Tendulkar (surname).
Page semi-protected
Sachin Tendulkar
Sachin at Castrol Golden Spanner Awards (crop).jpg
Tendulkar at an awards event in January 2013
Personal information
Full name	Sachin Ramesh Tendulkar
Born	 24 April 1973 (age 41)[1]
Bombay, Maharashtra, India
Nickname	Tendlya, God of Cricket,[2][3] Little Master,[1] Master Blaster[4][5]
Height	5 ft 5 in (165 cm)
Batting style	Right-handed
Bowling style	Right-arm medium, leg break, off break
Role	Batsman
International information
National side	
India
Test debut (cap 187)	15 November 1989 v Pakistan
Last Test	14 November 2013 v West Indies
ODI debut (cap 74)	18 December 1989 v Pakistan
Last ODI	18 March 2012 v Pakistan
ODI shirt no.	10
Only T20I (cap 11)	1 December 2006 v South Africa
Domestic team information
Years	Team
1988	Cricket Club of India
1988–2013	Mumbai
1992	Yorkshire
2008–2013	Mumbai Indians
Career statistics
Competition	Test	ODI	FC	LA
Matches	200	463	310	551
Runs scored	15,921	18,426	25,396	21,999
Batting average	53.79	44.83	57.92	45.54
100s/50s	51/68	49/96	81/116	60/114
Top score	248*	200*	248*	200*
Balls bowled	4,240	8,054	7,563	10,230
Wickets	46	154	71	201
Bowling average	54.17	44.48	62.18	42.17
5 wickets in innings	0	2	0	2
10 wickets in match	0	n/a	0	n/a
Best bowling	3/10	5/32	3/10	5/32
Catches/stumpings	115/–	140/–	186/–	175/–
Source: Cricinfo, 15 November 2013
Sachin Ramesh Tendulkar (Listeni/ˌsətʃɪn tɛnˈduːlkər/; born 24 April 1973) is a former Indian cricketer widely acknowledged as one of the greatest batsmen of all time, popularly holding the title "God of Cricket" among his fans.[2] Some commentators, such as former West Indian batsman Brian Lara, have labelled Tendulkar the greatest cricketer of all time.[6][7][8][9] He took up cricket at the age of eleven, made his Test debut against Pakistan at the age of sixteen, and went on to represent Mumbai domestically and India internationally for close to twenty-four years. He is the only player to have scored one hundred international centuries, the first batsman to score a double century in a One Day International, the only player to complete more than 30,000 runs in international cricket.[10] and the 16th player and first Indian to aggregate 50,000 runs or more in all forms of domestic and international recognised cricket.[11]

In 2002, Wisden Cricketers' Almanack ranked him the second greatest Test batsman of all time, behind Don Bradman, and the second greatest ODI batsman of all time, behind Viv Richards.[12] Later in his career, Tendulkar was a part of the Indian team that won the 2011 World Cup, his first win in six World Cup appearances for India.[13] He had previously been named "Player of the Tournament" at the 2003 edition of the tournament, held in South Africa. In 2013, he was the only Indian cricketer included in an all-time Test World XI named to mark the 150th anniversary of Wisden Cricketers' Almanack.[14][15][16]

Tendulkar received the Arjuna Award in 1994 for his outstanding sporting achievement, the Rajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna award in 1997, India's highest sporting honour, and the Padma Shri and Padma Vibhushan awards in 1999 and 2008, respectively, India's fourth and second highest civilian awards. After a few hours of his final match on 16 November 2013, the Prime Minister's Office announced the decision to award him the Bharat Ratna, India's highest civilian award.[17][18] He is the youngest recipient to date and the first ever sportsperson to receive the award.[19][20] He also won the 2010 Sir Garfield Sobers Trophy for cricketer of the year at the ICC awards.[21] In 2012, Tendulkar was nominated to the Rajya Sabha</textblock>
  </project>
</projects>